<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Kubernetes | Archived Blog Posts]]></title>
  <link href="http://tdongsi.github.io/javascript/blog/categories/kubernetes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tdongsi.github.io/javascript/"/>
  <updated>2021-03-11T15:03:36-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://tdongsi.github.io/javascript/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cuong Dong-Si]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes: Kube-router]]></title>
    <link href="http://tdongsi.github.io/javascript/blog/2017/05/15/kubernetes-kube-router/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-15T10:52:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tdongsi.github.io/javascript/blog/2017/05/15/kubernetes-kube-router</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kubernetes is one of the <a href="http://www.infoworld.com/article/3118345/cloud-computing/why-kubernetes-is-winning-the-container-war.html">most active open-source project</a> right now.
I&rsquo;m trying to keep up with interesting updates from the Kubernetes community.
This <code>kube-router</code> project is one of them although I&rsquo;ve not get an idea how stable or useful it is.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Kube-router is a distributed load balancer, firewall and router for Kubernetes. Kube-router can be configured to provide on each cluster node:<br/>* IPVS/LVS based service proxy on each node for ClusterIP and NodePort service types, providing service discovery and load balancing<br/>* an ingress firewall for the pods running on the node as per the defined Kubernetes network policies using iptables and ipset<br/>* a BGP router to advertise and learn the routes to the pod IP&rsquo;s for cross-node pod-to-pod connectivity</p></blockquote></p>

<!--more-->


<p>A few notes on related works in Kubernetes community:</p>

<ul>
<li>The most obvious one is <code>kube-proxy</code> service, which is included in the standard Kubernetes installations. This <code>kube-router</code> can be a replacement for <code>kube-proxy</code> in the future.</li>
<li>Another related work is <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/issues/44063">IPVS-based in-cluster service load balancing</a>.
Huawei presented this work at Kubecon 2016.
IIRC, it is implemented as a flag to kube-proxy and considerable performance improvement was reported.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
